which stands for bi-directional encoder
양방향 인코더를 나타냅니다.
representations for transformers.
변압기에 대한 표현.
Vert is a language model developed by Google in 2018.
Vert는 Google이 2018년에 개발한 언어 모델입니다.
It is considered one of the most significant breakthroughs
가장 중요한 혁신 중 하나로 간주됩니다.
in the area of natural language processing.
자연어 처리 분야에서요.
It caused a paradigm shift by introducing a new approach
새로운 접근 방식을 도입하여 패러다임 전환을 일으켰습니다.
to tackling language understanding tasks,
언어 이해 과제를 다루기 위해,
portraying large copies of text data,
텍스트 데이터의 대용량 사본을 표현하고,
and then funtuning for specific tasks,
그런 다음 특정 작업에 맞게 조정하고,
such as question answering and sediment analysis.
질의 응답, 퇴적물 분석 등.
This approach has proven to be highly effective
이 접근 방식은 매우 효과적인 것으로 입증되었습니다.
and has been the foundation
그리고 기초가 되었어요
for many subsequent advancements in LP.
LP의 이후 많은 발전을 위해.
Here's an illustration of Bert's pre-training
다음은 Bert의 사전 훈련을 보여주는 그림입니다.
and funtuning process,
그리고 펀튜닝 과정,
which I will explain in more detail in the following slides.
이에 대해서는 다음 슬라이드에서 자세히 설명하겠습니다.
So Bert is built on the transformer architecture,
그래서 Bert는 트랜스포머 아키텍처를 기반으로 구축되었습니다.
which is a type of neural network
신경망의 일종이다
that has shown great promise in subsequent sequence tasks.
이는 후속 시퀀스 작업에서 큰 가능성을 보여주었습니다.
Since we have already covered the transformer architecture
우리는 이미 변환기 아키텍처를 다루었으므로
in our previous lecture,
지난 강의에서,
I brief recap its key components.
주요 구성 요소를 간략하게 요약하겠습니다.
So the transformer consists of an encoder and a decoder,
따라서 변환기는 인코더와 디코더로 구성되며,
which are composed of multiple layers of self-attention
self-attention의 여러 층으로 구성됨
and the feed-forward neural networks.
그리고 피드포워드 신경망.
The encoder processes the input sequence
인코더는 입력 시퀀스를 처리합니다.
and generates a sequence of hidden representations.
일련의 숨겨진 표현을 생성합니다.
While the decoder generates output sequence
디코더가 출력 시퀀스를 생성하는 동안
based on the encoder's representations,
인코더의 표현을 기반으로,
following the initial success of the transformer
변압기의 초기 성공 이후
in machine translation tasks,
기계 번역 작업에서는
researchers explored using the decoder part of the transformer
연구원들은 변환기의 디코더 부분을 사용하여 탐구했습니다.
as a standalone language model.
독립형 언어 모델로.
So this led to the development of models
그래서 이것이 모델의 개발로 이어졌습니다.
like OpenAI's GBT1, the generative pre-trained transformer,
OpenAI의 GBT1과 같은 생성적 사전 훈련된 변환기는
which demonstrates the effectiveness
효과를 보여주는 것
of using the transformer decoder for language model.
언어 모델에 변환기 디코더를 사용하는 방법.
GBT1, however, was unidirectional,
그러나 GBT1은 단방향이었습니다.
meaning it could only attend to previous tokens
이는 이전 토큰에만 주의를 기울일 수 있음을 의미합니다.
in the sequence.
순서대로.
This choice is natural for next-world predictions,
이러한 선택은 다음 세계 예측에 있어 자연스러운 일입니다.
but it also has limitations.
그러나 그것은 또한 한계가 있습니다.
So we'll discuss this in more detail in the next slide.
따라서 다음 슬라이드에서 이에 대해 더 자세히 논의하겠습니다.
So let's compare unidirectional
그럼 단방향을 비교해 보겠습니다.
and bidirectional language models.
양방향 언어 모델.
So unidirectional models like GBT1
따라서 GBT1과 같은 단방향 모델
build representations of words incrementally
단어 표현을 점진적으로 구축
based on the words that came before them in the sequence.
순서대로 앞에 나온 단어를 기반으로 합니다.
This means that the representation of each word
이는 각 단어의 표현을 의미합니다.
is influenced only by the words that preceded it.
앞에 나온 단어에만 영향을 받습니다.
While this approach works well for some tasks,
이 접근 방식은 일부 작업에는 적합하지만
it doesn't capture the full context
전체 맥락을 포착하지 못함
of a word within a sentence.
문장 속의 단어.
For example, consider the sentence,
예를 들어, 다음 문장을 생각해 보세요.
I went to the bank to deposit money.
나는 돈을 입금하기 위해 은행에 갔다.
The ward bank could refer to a financial institution
와드 은행은 금융 기관을 의미할 수 있습니다.
or the side of a river.
아니면 강변.
And the money is determined by the context
그리고 돈은 상황에 따라 결정됩니다
of the whole sentence for tasks that require
필요한 작업에 대한 전체 문장 중
understanding the meaning of a word
단어의 의미를 이해하기
in the context of the entire sentence,
전체 문장의 맥락에서,
such as question answering or natural language inference.
질문 응답이나 자연어 추론과 같은 것입니다.
Unidirectional model may struggle.
단방향 모델은 어려움을 겪을 수 있습니다.
So this is where bidirectional models like BERT come in.
이것이 바로 BERT와 같은 양방향 모델이 등장하는 곳입니다.
So for such models, the representations of each word
따라서 이러한 모델의 경우 각 단어의 표현은
are built by considering the entire input sequence.
전체 입력 순서를 고려하여 구축됩니다.
Both the words that precede and follow the target words.
대상 단어 앞과 뒤의 단어 모두입니다.
So this allows the model to capture a richer context
이를 통해 모델은 더 풍부한 컨텍스트를 포착할 수 있습니다.
for each word, which can be beneficial
각 단어마다 유익할 수 있습니다.
for a wide range of NLP tasks.
광범위한 NLP 작업을 위한 것입니다.
However, building a bidirectional language model
그러나 양방향 언어 모델 구축
comes with its own set of challenges,
그 자체로 일련의 과제가 있습니다.
which we'll discuss in the next slides.
이에 대해서는 다음 슬라이드에서 논의하겠습니다.
So ELMO, which we discussed before,
그래서 앞서 논의한 ELMO는
was one of the first successful attempts
첫 번째 성공적인 시도 중 하나였습니다.
at building a bidirectional language model.
양방향 언어 모델을 구축할 때.
However, it aggregated the representations
그러나 그 표현을 종합해 보면
from different directions in an isolated manner,
서로 다른 방향에서 고립된 방식으로
which limited its ability to capture complex dependency
복잡한 종속성을 포착하는 능력이 제한되었습니다.
between words.
단어 사이.
BERT addressed these limitations
BERT는 이러한 제한 사항을 해결했습니다.
by replacing LSTMs with the transformer architecture.
LSTM을 변환기 아키텍처로 대체합니다.
In particular, BERT uses the multi-layer transformer encoder
특히 BERT는 다층 변압기 인코더를 사용합니다.
to build a deep bidirectional language model,
심층적인 양방향 언어 모델을 구축하기 위해,
which captures the context of each word
각 단어의 맥락을 포착하는
by considering every other word in the input sequence.
입력 순서의 다른 모든 단어를 고려하여.
This architecture allows BERT to generate
이 아키텍처를 통해 BERT는 다음을 생성할 수 있습니다.
rich contextualized representations of words,
풍부한 문맥화된 단어 표현,
which can be used for a wide range of NLP tasks.
이는 광범위한 NLP 작업에 사용될 수 있습니다.
The BERT input representation consists of three key components.
BERT 입력 표현은 세 가지 주요 구성 요소로 구성됩니다.
Token embeddings, segment embeddings,
토큰 임베딩, 세그먼트 임베딩,
and position embeddings.
및 위치 임베딩.
Token embeddings are the word embeddings
토큰 임베딩은 단어 임베딩입니다.
for each token in the input sequence.
입력 시퀀스의 각 토큰에 대해.
BERT uses word piece embedding
BERT는 단어 조각 임베딩을 사용합니다.
with a vocabulary size of 30,000 tokens.
어휘 크기는 30,000개 토큰입니다.
It is a subword tokenization method
하위 단어 토큰화 방법입니다.
that allows the model to handle out of vocabulary words
모델이 어휘 단어를 처리할 수 있게 해줍니다.
and capture morphological variation of words.
단어의 형태학적 변화를 포착합니다.
The input sequence is also augmented with special tokens,
입력 시퀀스는 특수 토큰으로도 강화됩니다.
such as CRS and SAP,
CRS, SAP 등
which are used to denote the beginning
시작을 나타내는 데 사용되는 것
and the separation of sentences, respectively.
그리고 문장의 분리.
So the CRS token is particularly important,
그래서 CRS 토큰이 특히 중요합니다.
because it is used to generate a fixed size representation
고정된 크기 표현을 생성하는 데 사용되기 때문입니다.
of the entire input sequence,
전체 입력 시퀀스 중
which can be used as an input to downstream tasks.
이는 다운스트림 작업에 대한 입력으로 사용될 수 있습니다.
Segment embeddings are used to distinguish
세그먼트 임베딩은 구별하는 데 사용됩니다.
between different sentences in the input sequence.
입력 시퀀스의 서로 다른 문장 사이.
This allows BERT to handle tasks
이를 통해 BERT는 작업을 처리할 수 있습니다.
that involve multiple sentences,
여러 문장이 포함된
such as natural language inference.
자연어 추론과 같은 것입니다.
Finally, position embeddings are added
마지막으로 위치 임베딩이 추가되었습니다.
to the token embeddings to capture the position
위치를 포착하기 위해 토큰 임베딩에
of each token in the input sequence.
입력 시퀀스의 각 토큰.
Different from traditional position embeddings,
기존의 포지션 임베딩과는 다르게,
BERT uses learned position embeddings,
BERT는 학습된 위치 임베딩을 사용합니다.
which are optimized during the pre-training process.
이는 사전 훈련 과정에서 최적화됩니다.
So BERT comes in two sizes, BERT-BASE and BERT-LARGE.
따라서 BERT는 BERT-BASE와 BERT-LARGE의 두 가지 크기로 제공됩니다.
BERT-BASE has 12 transformer layers
BERT-BASE에는 12개의 변압기 레이어가 있습니다.
and 768 hidden units,
768개의 히든 유닛,
and 12 self-attention heads,
12개의 셀프 어텐션 헤드,
which in total result in 110 million parameters.
총 1억 1천만 개의 매개변수가 생성됩니다.
BERT-LARGE, on the other hand, has 24 transformer layers.
반면 BERT-LARGE에는 24개의 변압기 레이어가 있습니다.
1024 hidden units and 16 self-attention heads
1024개의 히든 유닛과 16개의 셀프 어텐션 헤드
resulting in 340 million parameters.
결과적으로 3억 4천만 개의 매개변수가 생성됩니다.
The larger model has been shown to achieve
더 큰 모델이 달성되는 것으로 나타났습니다.
better performance on various NLP tasks,
다양한 NLP 작업에서 더 나은 성능,
but it also requires more computational resources
하지만 더 많은 계산 리소스가 필요합니다.
and longer training times.
그리고 더 긴 훈련 시간.
Back in 2018, BERT-LARGE was considered
2018년에는 BERT-LARGE가 고려되었습니다.
one of the largest model in the field.
해당 분야에서 가장 큰 모델 중 하나입니다.
However, with the continuous scaling of the language models,
그러나 언어 모델의 지속적인 확장으로 인해
we have seen even larger models being developed,
우리는 훨씬 더 큰 모델이 개발되는 것을 보았습니다.
such as GPT-3, which has 175 billion parameters,
1,750억 개의 매개변수가 있는 GPT-3와 같은
about 500 times more than the BERT-LARGE.
BERT-LARGE보다 약 500배 더 많습니다.
Both models are pre-trained on large copies of text data,
두 모델 모두 대용량 텍스트 데이터 사본에 대해 사전 학습되어 있습니다.
such as Wikipedia and the book covers,
Wikipedia 및 책 표지와 같은
using two unsupervised learning objectives,
두 가지 비지도 학습 목표를 사용하여
mass language modeling, and the next sentence prediction.
대량 언어 모델링 및 다음 문장 예측.
So the traditional approach to language modeling
따라서 언어 모델링에 대한 전통적인 접근 방식은
is to predict the next wording sequence
다음 단어 순서를 예측하는 것입니다
given the previous words.
이전 단어가 주어졌습니다.
So why this approach works well
그렇다면 이 접근 방식이 효과적인 이유는 무엇입니까?
for unidirectional language models?
단방향 언어 모델의 경우?
It is not suitable for bi-directional models like BERT.
BERT와 같은 양방향 모델에는 적합하지 않습니다.
But because conditioning on the future war
하지만 미래의 전쟁을 조건으로 하기 때문에
would result in data leakage during pre-training,
사전 훈련 중에 데이터 유출이 발생할 수 있습니다.
to address this issue,
이 문제를 해결하기 위해,
BERT introduces a new pre-training objective
BERT는 새로운 사전 훈련 목표를 도입합니다
called a mass language modeling, MLM.
대량 언어 모델링(MLM)이라고 합니다.
So in MLM, a random subset of the input tokens are massed,
따라서 MLM에서는 입력 토큰의 무작위 하위 집합이 집단화됩니다.
and the model is trying to predict the original words
모델은 원래 단어를 예측하려고 합니다.
based on their context.
상황에 따라.
This allows BERT to capture bi-directional context
이를 통해 BERT는 양방향 컨텍스트를 캡처할 수 있습니다.
while pre-training,
사전 훈련을 하는 동안,
but the model has to learn to predict the massed words
하지만 모델은 대량의 단어를 예측하는 방법을 학습해야 합니다.
based on both the preceding and the following words.
이전 단어와 다음 단어를 모두 기반으로 합니다.
In the original BERT paper,
원래 BERT 논문에서는
about 15% of the tokens are massed during pre-training.
토큰의 약 15%가 사전 훈련 중에 대량으로 생성됩니다.
Since the mass token is not presented in the input
대량 토큰이 입력에 표시되지 않기 때문에
during fine-tuning,
미세 조정하는 동안,
which may cause a mismatch between pre-training
사전 훈련 간의 불일치가 발생할 수 있습니다.
and fine-tuning,
미세 조정하고,
the BERT uses the following strategy
BERT는 다음 전략을 사용합니다
to handle the mass tokens.
대량 토큰을 처리합니다.
80% of the time, the token is replaced with a mass token.
80%의 경우 토큰은 대량 토큰으로 대체됩니다.
10% of the time, the token is replaced with a random token.
10%의 경우 토큰은 무작위 토큰으로 대체됩니다.
10% of the time, the token is left unchanged.
10%의 경우 토큰은 변경되지 않은 채로 남아 있습니다.
So this strategy encouraged the model
따라서 이 전략은 모델을 장려했습니다.
to learn robust representations of the mass tokens,
대량 토큰의 강력한 표현을 학습하기 위해,
which can be beneficial for downstream tasks.
이는 다운스트림 작업에 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
In addition to mass language modeling,
대량 언어 모델링 외에도
BERT also uses the next sentence prediction,
BERT는 다음 문장 예측도 사용합니다.
NISP objectives during pre-training.
사전 훈련 중 NISP 목표.
In NISP, the model is trying to predict
NISP에서 모델은 예측을 시도합니다.
whether a pair of sentences are consecutive
한 쌍의 문장이 연속되는지 여부
in their original document or not.
원본 문서에 있든 없든.
During pre-training,
사전 훈련 중에,
50% of the training examples are positive examples,
학습 예시의 50%는 긍정적 예시입니다.
while the second sentence follows the first sentence
두 번째 문장이 첫 번째 문장 뒤에 오는 동안
in the original document,
원본 문서에서는
and the 50% are negative examples,
50%는 부정적인 예입니다.
where the second sentence is readily sampled
두 번째 문장이 쉽게 샘플링되는 곳
for the coppers.
구리를 위해.
This objective encourages the model
이 목표는 모델을 장려합니다
to capture relationships between sentences,
문장 사이의 관계를 포착하기 위해,
which can be beneficial for downstream tasks
이는 다운스트림 작업에 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
such as question altering and a natural language inferences,
질문 변경, 자연어 추론 등
where understanding the relationship
관계를 이해하는 곳
between sentences is crucial.
문장 사이가 중요합니다.
So once pre-trained, BERT can be fine-tuned
따라서 일단 사전 훈련되면 BERT를 미세 조정할 수 있습니다.
for a specific task using supervised learning.
지도 학습을 사용하여 특정 작업을 수행합니다.
The fine-tuning process involves adding
미세 조정 프로세스에는 추가 작업이 포함됩니다.
a task-specific output layer
작업별 출력 레이어
on top of the pre-trained BERT model,
사전 훈련된 BERT 모델 위에
and fine-tuning the entire model
전체 모델을 미세 조정하고
on the label dataset for target task.
대상 작업에 대한 레이블 데이터 세트에 대해
The task-specific output layer can be a single layer
작업별 출력 레이어는 단일 레이어일 수 있습니다.
or multiple layers,
또는 여러 레이어,
depending on the complexity of the task.
작업의 복잡성에 따라 다릅니다.
In the original BERT paper,
원래 BERT 논문에서는
the authors demonstrate the effectiveness
저자는 효율성을 입증합니다.
of fine-tuning BERT on a wide range of NLP tasks,
광범위한 NLP 작업에 대한 BERT 미세 조정,
such as sentence parallel classification,
문장 병렬 분류와 같은
single sentence classification,
단일 문장 분류,
question altering, and a sequence tagging.
질문 변경 및 시퀀스 태깅.
The token-level task,
토큰 수준 작업,
such as question altering and a sequence tagging,
질문 변경 및 시퀀스 태깅과 같은
uses the token-level representations from BERT.
BERT의 토큰 수준 표현을 사용합니다.
The wide-sentence-level tasks,
넓은 문장 수준의 작업,
such as sentence parallel classification,
문장 병렬 분류와 같은
use the CRS token representation
CRS 토큰 표현 사용
as the input to the task-specific output layer.
작업별 출력 레이어에 대한 입력으로 사용됩니다.
So the original BERT paper reported
그래서 원본 BERT 논문은 보고했습니다.
the state-of-the-art results on a wide range
광범위한 분야에서 최첨단 결과를
of NLP benchmarks, including the GRU benchmark,
GRU 벤치마크를 포함한 NLP 벤치마크 중
which consists of nine different tasks,
9개의 서로 다른 작업으로 구성되어 있으며,
such as question altering, natural language inference,
질문 변경, 자연어 추론,
and sentiment analysis.
그리고 감정 분석.
BERT achieved significant improvements
BERT는 상당한 개선을 달성했습니다.
over previous models of most of the tasks.
대부분의 작업에 대한 이전 모델에 비해.
In particular, BERT large outform
특히, BERT 대규모 아웃폼
all other models on the GRU benchmark,
GRU 벤치마크의 다른 모든 모델,
demonstrating the effectiveness
효과를 입증하는
of large-scale pre-training for NLP tasks.
NLP 작업을 위한 대규모 사전 훈련.
The success of BERT fundamentally changed
BERT의 성공은 근본적으로 바뀌었습니다
the landscape of NLP research
NLP 연구의 풍경
and led to the development of many other language models
다른 많은 언어 모델의 개발로 이어졌습니다.
that built on their BERT architecture.
BERT 아키텍처를 기반으로 구축되었습니다.
So following the success of BERT,
따라서 BERT의 성공에 따라
several variants have been developed
여러 가지 변형이 개발되었습니다
to address its limitations and improve its performance.
한계를 해결하고 성능을 향상시킵니다.
So here's an illustration of the BERT family tree,
여기 BERT 가계도에 대한 그림이 있습니다.
which shows the evolution of BERT and its variants.
이는 BERT와 그 변형의 진화를 보여줍니다.
In the next few slides,
다음 몇 개의 슬라이드에서는
we'll discuss some of the most notable BERT variants,
가장 주목할만한 BERT 변형에 대해 논의하겠습니다.
including Roberta, Albert,
로베르타, 앨버트를 비롯해
Electra, and Ernie.
엘렉트라와 어니.
Roberta, which stands for a robustly-optimized
로버타(Roberta)는 견고하게 최적화된 모델을 의미합니다.
BERT pre-training approach,
BERT 사전 훈련 접근법,
is a variant of BERT's developed by Facebook AI.
Facebook AI가 개발한 BERT의 변형입니다.
It is one of the most widely used BERT variants
가장 널리 사용되는 BERT 변종 중 하나입니다.
and has achieved state-of-the-art results
그리고 최고 수준의 성과를 달성했습니다.
on many NLP benchmarks.
많은 NLP 벤치마크에서
Roberta builds on the BERT architecture
Roberta는 BERT 아키텍처를 기반으로 구축되었습니다.
and introduces several modifications to the design
디자인에 몇 가지 수정 사항을 도입합니다.
and pre-training process of BERT.
BERT의 사전 훈련 과정.
In addition, the BERT architecture
또한 BERT 아키텍처는
introduces several modifications to the design
디자인에 여러 가지 수정 사항을 적용합니다.
and the pre-training process of BERT.
그리고 BERT의 사전 훈련 과정.
In addition, it introduces a new pre-training data set
또한 새로운 사전 훈련 데이터 세트를 도입했습니다.
called CCNEWS,
CCNEWS라고 불리는데,
which consists of 63 million
6300만개로 구성
English news articles proud from the web.
웹에서 자랑스러운 영어 뉴스 기사.
The author of Roberta conducted an extensive study
Roberta의 저자는 광범위한 연구를 수행했습니다.
to identify the impact of different design choices
다양한 디자인 선택의 영향을 확인하기 위해
and the pre-training data on the performance of BERT.
BERT 성능에 대한 사전 훈련 데이터입니다.
They found that by optimizing the pre-training process
그들은 사전 훈련 과정을 최적화함으로써
and the training on a larger data set,
더 큰 데이터 세트에 대한 교육,
they could achieve significant improvements
상당한 개선을 이룰 수 있었습니다
over the original BERT model.
원래 BERT 모델에 비해
Here are some of the key modifications introduced in Roberta.
다음은 Roberta에 도입된 주요 수정 사항 중 일부입니다.
I will discuss a few of them in more detail
그 중 몇 가지에 대해 더 자세히 논의하겠습니다.
in the following slides.
다음 슬라이드에서 확인해보세요.
One of the key differences between Roberta and BERT
Roberta와 BERT의 주요 차이점 중 하나
is the way they handle masked language modeling
마스크된 언어 모델링을 처리하는 방식입니다.
during pre-training.
사전 훈련 중.
In other words, the masking is performed
즉, 마스킹이 수행됩니다.
during the data pre-processing step,
데이터 전처리 단계에서
which results in a fixed set of masked tokens
그 결과 고정된 마스킹된 토큰 세트가 생성됩니다.
for each training epoch.
각 훈련 에포크마다.
To avoid using the same masked tokens
동일한 마스킹된 토큰을 사용하지 않으려면
for each training epoch,
각 훈련 에포크마다
BERT ad hocly duplicates the input data 10 times
BERT는 입력 데이터를 임시로 10번 복제합니다.
and masks different tokens in each duplicate.
각 복제본에 서로 다른 토큰을 마스크합니다.
In contrast, Roberta uses dynamic masking,
대조적으로 Roberta는 동적 마스킹을 사용합니다.
where the masking is generated every time
매번 마스킹이 생성되는 곳
the input is fed into the model during pre-training.
사전 훈련 중에 입력이 모델에 공급됩니다.
This allows Roberta to use different masked tokens
이를 통해 Roberta는 다양한 마스크 토큰을 사용할 수 있습니다.
for each training epoch,
각 훈련 에포크마다
which can be beneficial for learning robust representations
이는 강력한 표현을 학습하는 데 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
of the masked tokens.
마스크된 토큰의
The authors of Roberta found that dynamic masking
Roberta의 저자는 동적 마스킹을 발견했습니다.
led to better performance compared to static masking.
정적 마스킹에 비해 성능이 향상되었습니다.
Multiple studies have questioned the effectiveness
여러 연구에서 효과에 의문을 제기했습니다.
of the next sentence prediction objective in BERT.
BERT의 다음 문장 예측 목표.
To investigate the impact of NSP,
NSP의 영향을 조사하기 위해,
the authors of Roberta conducted experiments
Roberta의 저자는 실험을 수행했습니다.
with different input formats and pre-training objectives.
다양한 입력 형식과 사전 훈련 목표를 가지고 있습니다.
Here are the four settings they considered.
그들이 고려한 네 가지 설정은 다음과 같습니다.
Segment pair plus NSP,
세그먼트 쌍과 NSP,
which is the original BERT input format
원래 BERT 입력 형식입니다.
with NSP objectives.
NSP 목표를 가지고 있습니다.
Each training example consists of a pair of segments,
각 훈련 예시는 한 쌍의 세그먼트로 구성됩니다.
which can contain multiple natural sentences.
여러 개의 자연스러운 문장을 포함할 수 있습니다.
And sentence pair plus NSP.
그리고 문장 쌍에 NSP를 더한 것입니다.
So each training example consists of a pair of natural sentences,
따라서 각 훈련 예제는 한 쌍의 자연 문장으로 구성됩니다.
either sampled consecutively from one document
하나의 문서에서 연속적으로 샘플링됨
or from different documents.
또는 다른 문서에서.
And full sentences.
그리고 완전한 문장.
So each training example consists of natural sentences,
그래서 각 훈련 예시는 자연스러운 문장으로 구성되어 있으며,
sampled consecutively from one or more documents
하나 이상의 문서에서 연속적으로 샘플링됨
up to a maximum length of 512 tokens
최대 길이는 512개 토큰입니다.
without the NSP objective.
NSP 목표 없이.
And the doc sentence,
그리고 문서 문장은,
so similar to full sentences,
완전한 문장과 비슷합니다.
but the sampling does not cross document boundaries
하지만 샘플링은 문서 경계를 넘지 않습니다.
and also without the NSP objective.
또한 NSP 목표가 없습니다.
So the authors found that the NSP objective
그래서 저자는 NSP 목표가
did not provide significant improvements
상당한 개선을 제공하지 못했습니다
over the other settings.
다른 설정보다.
And in some cases, it even heard the performance.
그리고 어떤 경우에는 공연을 듣기도 했습니다.
So they also found that using longer sequence
그래서 그들은 또한 더 긴 시퀀스를 사용하는 것을 발견했습니다.
during pre-training such as full sentences
완전한 문장과 같은 사전 훈련 중
or document level sentences
또는 문서 수준 문장
led to better performance
더 나은 성과로 이어졌습니다
compared to using individual sentence pairs.
개별 문장 쌍을 사용하는 것과 비교됩니다.
So based on this findings,
그래서 이번 조사 결과를 바탕으로
Roberta used the full sentence settings
Roberta는 전체 문장 설정을 사용했습니다.
without the NSP objective for pre-training.
사전 훈련을 위한 NSP 목표가 없습니다.
So in addition to the change
그래서 변화에 더해
in the pre-training objectives and input format,
사전 훈련 목표 및 입력 형식에서
Roberta also introduces several modifications
Roberta는 또한 몇 가지 수정 사항을 소개합니다.
to the pre-training process of BERT.
BERT의 사전 훈련 과정을 살펴보겠습니다.
So first, the authors found that using larger batch size
먼저 저자는 더 큰 배치 크기를 사용하는 것을 발견했습니다.
it leads to better pre-prenexity
그것은 더 나은 preprenexity로 이어진다
and downstream test performance.
및 다운스트림 테스트 성능.
Second, the authors found that the original BERT
둘째, 저자는 원래 BERT가
is under-trained
훈련이 부족하다
and using more data leads to better performance.
더 많은 데이터를 사용하면 성능이 향상됩니다.
In addition to the original BERT pre-training data,
원래의 BERT 사전 학습 데이터 외에도
Roberta used the CC News data set
Roberta는 CC News 데이터 세트를 사용했습니다.
which consists of 63 million English news articles.
6,300만 개의 영어 뉴스 기사로 구성되어 있습니다.
So finally, they also found that
그래서 마침내 그들은 또한 그것을 발견했습니다
the longer training leads to better performance.
훈련 시간이 길수록 성과가 향상됩니다.
They trained Roberta for 100,000,
그들은 Roberta를 100,000명에게 훈련시켰습니다.
so 300,000 and 500,000 steps.
그러니까 300,000걸음과 500,000걸음이군요.
They found that longer training leads to better performance
그들은 더 긴 훈련이 더 나은 성과로 이어진다는 것을 발견했습니다
on downstream tasks.
다운스트림 작업에 대해
Roberta did not show signs of overfitting
Roberta는 과적합 징후를 보이지 않았습니다.
even after 500,000 steps,
50만 걸음을 걸어도
which suggests that longer training could be beneficial
이는 더 긴 훈련이 유익할 수 있음을 시사합니다.
for large-scale language models.
대규모 언어 모델의 경우.
So the modifications introduced in Roberta
그래서 Roberta에 도입된 수정 사항은
led to significant improvements
상당한 개선을 가져왔습니다
over the original BERT model.
원래 BERT 모델에 비해
So Roberta achieved state-of-the-art
그래서 Roberta는 최첨단 기술을 달성했습니다.
on the glue benchmark,
접착제 벤치마크에서
surpassing BERT and other language models
BERT 및 기타 언어 모델을 능가함
on most of the tests.
대부분의 테스트에서.
Then the ALBERT.
그 다음은 알버트.
So ALBERT, which stands for a light BERT,
그래서 Light BERT를 뜻하는 ALBERT는,
is a variant of BERT
BERT의 변형입니다
developed by Google Research.
Google Research에서 개발했습니다.
So scaling up language models like BERT
따라서 BERT와 같은 언어 모델을 확장합니다.
to achieve better performance
더 나은 성능을 달성하기 위해
often comes with increased computational cost
종종 계산 비용이 증가합니다.
and memory requirements.
및 메모리 요구 사항.
ALBERT addressed this issue by introducing
ALBERT는 다음을 도입하여 이 문제를 해결했습니다.
several parameter reduction techniques
여러 매개변수 감소 기술
to make the model more efficient
모델을 더 효율적으로 만들기 위해
without compromising its effectiveness.
그 효율성을 손상시키지 않고.
The authors show that a configuration of ALBERT
저자는 ALBERT의 구성을 보여줍니다.
similar to BERT large
BERT 대형과 유사
can have up to 18 times fewer parameters
최대 18배 더 적은 매개변수를 가질 수 있습니다.
and can be trained up to 1.7 times faster.
최대 1.7배 더 빠르게 훈련할 수 있습니다.
So there are three key parameter reduction techniques
따라서 세 가지 주요 매개변수 감소 기술이 있습니다.
introduced in ALBERT,
ALBERT에서 소개되었으며,
factorized embedding parameterization,
인수분해된 임베딩 매개변수화,
translator, parameter sharing,
변환기, 매개변수 공유,
and interest-sentence coherence loss
및 관심-문장 일관성 손실
or sentence order prediction.
또는 문장 순서 예측.
So I will discuss each of these techniques
그래서 저는 이러한 각 기술에 대해 논의하겠습니다.
in more detail in the following slides.
다음 슬라이드에서 자세히 알아보세요.
So the first parameter reduction techniques
따라서 첫 번째 매개변수 감소 기술은
introduced in ALBERT
ALBERT에 소개됨
is factorized embedding parameterization.
인수분해된 임베딩 매개변수화입니다.
In BERT,
BERT에서는
the dimensions of the token embeddings
토큰 임베딩의 차원
and the hidden layers are the same,
히든 레이어는 동일합니다.
which is a sub-automode choice.
이는 하위 자동 모드 선택입니다.
The token embeddings are used to represent
토큰 임베딩은 다음을 나타내는 데 사용됩니다.
the input tokens and only capture
입력 토큰 및 캡처만
the context-free information of the tokens.
토큰의 컨텍스트 없는 정보.
On the other hand, the hidden layers
반면에 은닉층은
are used to capture the context-dependent
상황에 따른 캡처에 사용됩니다.
information of the tokens.
토큰 정보입니다.
The power of BERT comes from the hidden layer
BERT의 힘은 숨겨진 레이어에서 나옵니다.
and not the token embedding.
토큰 임베딩이 아닙니다.
So it is natural that the hidden layers
그러니 은닉층이 생기는 것은 당연하다.
should have a higher dimension than the token embeddings.
토큰 임베딩보다 더 높은 차원을 가져야 합니다.
However, to increase the dimension of the hidden layers,
하지만 은닉층의 차원을 늘리기 위해
the dimension of the token embeddings
토큰 임베딩의 차원
must also be increased.
또한 증가해야합니다.
This would result in a significant increase
이로 인해 상당한 증가가 발생할 것입니다.
in the number of parameters
매개변수의 수
because the vocabulary size is usually very large.
일반적으로 어휘 크기가 매우 크기 때문입니다.
So for example,
예를 들어,
BERT has a vocabulary size of 30,000 tokens
BERT의 어휘 크기는 30,000개 토큰입니다.
and they use 768-dimensional token embeddings,
768차원 토큰 임베딩을 사용합니다.
resulting in 23 million parameters.
결과적으로 2,300만 개의 매개변수가 생성됩니다.
So BERT addresses this issue
그래서 BERT는 이 문제를 해결합니다.
by decoupling the dimension of the token embeddings
토큰 임베딩의 차원을 분리하여
from the dimensions of the hidden layers.
숨겨진 레이어의 차원에서.
So in BERT,
그래서 BERT에서는
the token embeddings are first projected
토큰 임베딩이 먼저 예상됩니다.
to a lower-dimensional space
저차원 공간으로
and then projected to the higher-dimensional space
그런 다음 더 높은 차원의 공간으로 투영됩니다.
of the hidden layers.
숨겨진 레이어 중.
This allows BERT to use a higher-dimensional hidden layer
이를 통해 BERT는 더 높은 차원의 숨겨진 레이어를 사용할 수 있습니다.
without significantly increasing the number of parameters.
매개변수 수를 크게 늘리지 않고.
So using this technique,
그래서 이 기술을 사용하면,
the number of parameters is reduced from
매개변수 수가 다음에서 감소합니다.
the big O of the V times H
V 곱하기 H의 큰 O
to the big O of the V times E plus H times E.
V 곱하기 E 더하기 H 곱하기 E의 큰 O입니다.
So where V is the vocabulary size
여기서 V는 어휘 크기입니다.
and H is the hidden layer dimension
H는 숨겨진 레이어 차원입니다.
and E is embedding dimension.
E는 임베딩 차원입니다.
The second parameter reduction technique
두 번째 매개변수 감소 기법
introduced in BERT is cross-layer parameter sharing.
BERT에 도입된 것은 크로스 레이어 매개변수 공유입니다.
So in BERT,
그래서 BERT에서는
each layer has its own set of parameters,
각 레이어에는 고유한 매개변수 세트가 있습니다.
which results in a large number of parameters.
이로 인해 많은 수의 매개변수가 발생합니다.
Albert addresses this issue
Albert가 이 문제를 해결합니다.
by sharing parameters across layers.
레이어 간에 매개변수를 공유함으로써
There are several ways to share parameters across layers,
레이어 간에 매개변수를 공유하는 방법에는 여러 가지가 있습니다.
such as sharing the attention waves,
관심의 물결을 공유하는 것,
the feed-over neural network waves, or both.
피드오버 신경망 파동 또는 둘 다.
By default,
기본적으로,
Albert shares all parameters across layers.
Albert는 여러 레이어에서 모든 매개변수를 공유합니다.
The authors found that this parameter sharing technique
저자는 이 매개변수 공유 기술을 발견했습니다.
led to a significant parameter reduction
상당한 매개변수 감소로 이어졌습니다.
without compromising the performance of the model
모델의 성능을 저하시키지 않고
significantly.
상당히.
And the third parameter reduction technique introduced
그리고 세 번째 매개변수 감소 기술이 도입되었습니다.
is interest sentence coherence,
관심 문장 일관성,
or sentence order prediction.
또는 문장 순서 예측.
So in BERT,
그래서 BERT에서는
the next sentence prediction objective
다음 문장 예측 목표
is used to encourage the model
모델을 격려하는 데 사용됩니다.
to capture relationship between sentences.
문장 사이의 관계를 포착합니다.
However, as we discussed earlier,
그러나 앞서 논의한 것처럼,
the NASP objective has been shown to be less effective
NASP 목표는 덜 효과적인 것으로 나타났습니다.
than other pre-training objectives.
다른 사전 훈련 목표보다
So Albert introduced a new pre-training objective
그래서 Albert는 새로운 사전 훈련 목표를 도입했습니다.
called a sentence order prediction,
문장 순서 예측이라고 합니다.
which is supposed to be more effective than NASP.
NASP보다 더 효과적이라고 합니다.
So in sentence order prediction,
그래서 문장 순서 예측에서는
the model is trying to predict
모델이 예측을 시도하고 있습니다.
whether a pair of sentences
한 쌍의 문장인지
are in the correct order or not.
순서가 맞는지 아닌지.
The authors found that these objectives
저자는 이러한 목표를 발견했습니다.
lead to better performance compared to NASP.
NASP에 비해 성능이 더 좋습니다.
And actually, this is not a parameter reduction technique,
그리고 사실 이건 매개변수 감소 기법이 아니고,
like to investigate whether the NASP objective
NASP 목표가 맞는지 조사하고 싶습니다.
is effective or not,
효과가 있든 없든,
similar to what the robot had did.
로봇이 했던 것과 비슷합니다.
So the parameter reduction techniques introduced
그래서 도입된 매개변수 감소 기술은
in Albert lead to a significant improvement
Albert의 경우 상당한 개선이 이루어졌습니다.
in efficiency without compromising
타협하지 않고 효율성을 높이다
the performance of the model.
모델의 성능.
So it even achieved the state-of-the-art results
그래서 최고 수준의 성과까지 달성했습니다.
on the group benchmark,
그룹 벤치마크에서는
surprising BERT, robot and other language models
놀라운 BERT, 로봇 및 기타 언어 모델
for most of the text.
대부분의 텍스트에 대해.
And this performance is quite impressive.
그리고 이 퍼포먼스는 꽤 인상적이다.